# Antonio Martinez

antonios.martinez.dev@gmail.com +506 6477 5014 San Jose, Costa Rica https://martinezantonio.github.io/,

Web developer (w2 form)

#### Summary

7 years of professional career as a web developer.

Good understanding of PHP and modern JavaScript (ES6), using OOP programming and MVC pattern design. Excellent debugging skills and good webmaster concepts (SSL, DNS, IP, Apache, Nginx, IIS, CGI).

MySQL databases design, normalization, administration, and SQL optimization.

Good understanding of web services and SOA-related standards like REST / OAuth / ISON.

Clean code and strong frontend skills (HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Angular CLI, Bootstrap, jQuery).

A day in my life may consist of: Work with JavaScript promises, design a responsive landing page, develop a custom WordPress plugin, adding an API endpoint, MySQL database design or normalization, read the documentation of new PHP releases, bugs find and fix, back up websites, programming new components or services, environment setting, files compression and optimization, take some Jira ticket, deployment, and some more cool stuff.

IDE stack: PhpStorm / WebStorm / Navicat / Postman.

## Professional experience

#### Web developer

MY BOOKIE • San Jose, Costa Rica

01/2021 - 04/2021

MyBookie Sportsbook & Casino. I was hired as a consultant and was in charge of important updates in the WordPress core of mybookie.ag. Working with the latest version of PHP 8.0 and Webpack JS.

#### Web developer

Jazz Gaming Solutions • San Jose, Costa Rica

01/2018 - 09/2020

I was responsible for developing, implementing, and maintaining mostly internal sportsbooks web applications like REST APIs, Websites, and Databases. I collaborated with technical and business staff in the design, development, testing, implementation, and production support of web applications in PHP, JavaScript, Angular CLI, HTML5, CSS3, Git, and some other cool technologies.

#### Web developer

PROFI • San Jose, Costa Rica

04/2014 - 02/2017

At PROFI, I mostly work with WordPress.

Working with project managers and designers, I was responsible for programming custom themes, custom plugins, mega menus, dashboards, reports, forms, landing pages, import, export, and backup websites.

### Web developer

CIP Reporting • Virginia, United States

08/2016 - 06/2017

At my current position, I am working on a web reporting system for casinos. Giving the maintenance and programming of new reports, new features, updates, and API integrations. We use technologies such as PHP, MySQL, jQuery, CSS, HTML, AJAX, JSON, Git. In addition to full-stack development, I also working on a lot of server-side tasks. I have helped to set up a lot of development environments and server configurations. (LAMP, WAMP).

# Web developer

Netsoft • San Jose, Costa Rica

03/2013 - 02/2014

Programming and maintaining ERP systems. The principal, Dolibarr, a very robust open-source made in PHP. I was responsible for things like, develop new custom reports, migrate and export data in JSON and SQL formats, modify MySQL databases, PHP SMTP emails, templates design with HTML and CSS, API integrations.

#### **Technologies**

- PHP
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Sass
- WordPress
- Jira
- Gitflow

- MySQL
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JSON
- Apache
- HTML5
- Angular CLI

LinkedIn Skill Assessment badge

#### **Education**

## **High school**

Liceo Ingeniero Manuel Benavides Rodriguez • San Jose, Costa Rica

Currently completing courses in computer science, robotics and statistics

Languages

• English • Spanish

**Projects** 

https://mybookie.ag

https://oddsandnews.com

https://plive.ganchrow.com

https://xbet.ag

https://www.cipreporting.com

https://jazzsports.ag

02/2015

https://scoresandodds.com

https://stayincostarica.com

https://tabacon.com